<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Portfolio]]></title><description><![CDATA[Software Development Engineer @ HashedIn]]></description><link>http://www.ombharatiya.codes/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 23:43:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to my Site!]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Namaste! I'm a Software Engineer and here to build some resilient softwares and systems. Let me quickly introduce myself without wasting your bytes.

]]></description><link>http://www.ombharatiya.codes//about-ombharatiya/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ombharatiya.codes//about-ombharatiya/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Namaste! I’m a Software Engineer and here to build some resilient softwares and systems. Let me quickly introduce myself without wasting your bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- end --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I ❤️ to build, else there’s nothing more exciting about me!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I written my first code when I was in class 8th. Ever since then, I’ve been obsessed with the idea of solving problems using software systems. I love Physics &amp;#x26; Mathematics as well but am little biased for Computer Science. This was a reason I dropped out from Degree in Physics Hons and got into Computer Science &amp;#x26; Engineering. I have been a well known guy in computer labs in my college and have fond for MOOCs. I write code in C++, Python, Java and JavaScript. Even I learnt C# &amp;#x26; Objective-C out of curiosity to learn app and game development during college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first industrial exposure was with Microsoft, when I was selected for the Student Partner Program and got hands on with Cloud &amp;#x26; AI. Ever since then my love for this field became stronger and I did few Hackathons &amp;#x26; community engagements as well that helped me gain confidence in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After one hackathon, I got opportunity to intern in the Software Development &amp;#x26; AI team of ISRO and worked on Deep Learning with CNN for Image semantic analysis and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later I joined HashedIn, a SaaS product based startup company, and have been a valuable Full Stack developer since then. I play key role in design &amp;#x26; development of Microservice based applications. My day to day job involves developing REST APIs in DJango and Python, building interactive React Applications &amp;#x26; using Docker &amp;#x26; AWS services for deployment. I’ve worked on noSQL databases including InfluxDB, MongoDB, DynamoDB, and RDBs like Postgres for my applications. I’m keen of learning in-depth of systems and models. I see myself as a learner and I always engage myself by enrolling for trending courses and completing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than being a Software Engineer, I love to get into discussions on Business, Entrepreneurship, Philosophy &amp;#x26; Socialpreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d prefer to discuss building product and innovative idea on coffee/beer than partying over weekend.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>